<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eduardo L. Acosta</title>
    <link>http://eacosta2758.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eduardo L. Acosta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://eacosta2758.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time and its discontents</title>
      <link>http://eacosta2758.github.io/teaching/01-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eacosta2758.github.io/teaching/01-time/</guid>
      <description>Course description     Time is fundamental to all ideas about the past and our projections to the future, yet our measures and conceptions of time change constantly. This class investigates how ideas, debates and everyday experiences of time, history and their periodization have taken shape in the intellectual exchange between South Asia and the West. We will explore key concepts and themes pertaining to the temporal cultures of medieval and modern South Asia, the differences and challenges that these ideas posed to the hegemonic Western world-view and how our modern notion of time, history and their everyday experiences were forged in this encounter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanskrit</title>
      <link>http://eacosta2758.github.io/teaching/02-sanskrit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eacosta2758.github.io/teaching/02-sanskrit/</guid>
      <description>Description     Here you will find a selection of handouts I created for students in the beginner and intermediate level of Sanskrit at The University of Chicago.
Sample of handouts     Aviayībhāva compound      Download PDF
Bahuvrīhi compound      Download PDF
Tatpuruṣa compound      Download PDF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>http://eacosta2758.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://eacosta2758.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Eduardo L. Acosta    Eduardo L. Acosta PhD. candidate in South Asian Languages and Civilizations The University of Chicago  Download PDF -- eacosta[at]uchicago[dot]edu  Education PhD South Asian Languages and Civilizations The University of Chicago 2015-2022 (expected) Dissertation: Medieval Landscapes: The Nadia Raj and the idea of the Middle Ages in Bengal, 18th - 19th centuries. Committee: Dipesh Chakrabarty (chair), Thibaut d’Hubert, Whitney Cox.
 Masters of Arts in Asian and African Studies El Colegio de Mexico 2011-2013 Specialization in South Asian Studies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
